Hello, English learners and welcome back to EnglishPod.
你好，英语学习者，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and today we're talking about money, but this time we're talking about
我是Catherine，今天我们谈论的是钱，但这次我们说的是
borrowing money.
借钱。
Right.
对。
So, we're asking for money.
所以，我们是在要钱。
We're going to the bank and we are asking for a loan.
我们要去银行申请贷款。
But before we go, why don't we take a look at vocabulary preview.
但在开始之前，我们先来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Okay, so a loan is some money that you get from the bank.
好的，贷款就是从银行拿到的一笔钱。
So we're talking about requesting a loan today.
所以我们今天说的是申请贷款。
Alright, so you request for a loan or you ask for a loan.
没错，所以你要申请贷款或者请求贷款。
Exactly.
正是。
So to request is to ask.
所以“request”就是“ask”的意思。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
And that's the word that we have for vocabulary preview.
这就是我们词汇预览中的那个词。
So let's listen to the dialogue for the first time.
那么，让我们第一次听一下对话。
Hello sir, may I help you?
先生您好，有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes, I would like some information for requesting a loan.
是的，我想了解一些关于申请贷款的信息。
Very well.
好的。
Here are the general terms of our loan policies.
这是我们贷款政策的一般条款。
We pride ourselves in having the lowest interest rate in the country for personal loans.
我们以拥有全国个人贷款最低利率而自豪。
I see.
我明白了。
So let me get this straight.
那么让我理清楚。
If I borrow, let's say, $10,000, how much will I have to pay each month?
如果我借，比如说，一万美元，我每个月要还多少钱？
It depends on how long you take to pay it back.
这取决于你多久还清。
If we lend you $10,000 at an annual interest rate of 10% for 48 months, you would have
如果我们借给你一万美元，年利率10%，分48个月还，你每个月
to pay each month a portion of the loan, which is called the principal, and another small
要还一部分贷款，这叫做本金，再加上一小部分
portion of the annual interest rate.
年利率。
This of course is considering that you don't default on a payment.
当然，这前提是你没有违约还款。
It sounds good, but there's just one problem.
听起来不错，但有一个问题。
I have a terrible credit score.
我的信用评分很差。
That is a very serious problem, you see.
那是个很严重的问题，你看。
The bank must assess your personal information, past loans, assets, and any other relevant
银行必须评估你的个人信息、过往贷款、资产以及任何其他相关
information, such as your credit score, in order to approve your loan.
信息，比如你的信用评分，才能批准你的贷款。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I don't really need the money.
我其实不需要这笔钱。
Thanks anyways.
还是谢谢了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now why don't we take a look at some of the key words that we'll find in Language
那么现在，我们来看看语言中会出现的一些关键词。
Takeaway.
外卖。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so on Language Takeaway today, we have a couple of different words.
好的，今天在语言要点部分，我们有几个不同的单词。
Why don't we start off with the loan policies?
我们不如先从贷款政策开始吧？
Okay, so a policy is like a rule.
好的，政策就像一条规则。
For example, a government can have policies, but in this case, a loan policy is the rules
例如，政府可以有政策，但在这里，贷款政策是关于你贷款的规则，
regarding the loan that you have.
涉及你拥有的贷款。
Right, so maybe the loan policies could include what's the maximum length of your loan, or
对，所以贷款政策可能包括贷款的最长期限，
maybe what's the annual interest rate, et cetera.
或者年利率等等。
How much you have to pay each month, like that.
你每个月要付多少钱，诸如此类。
Exactly.
没错。
So a policy is the rules related to the loan that you've taken out.
所以政策就是与你所借贷款相关的规则。
And we have some very, very important words following this, and they go together.
然后我们有一些非常重要的词，它们是一起出现的。
So the first word is to borrow.
第一个词是“借入”。
Okay, so you probably know this word already, to borrow.
好的，你可能已经知道这个词了，“借入”。
So can I borrow your pen?
我能借你的笔吗？
Can I borrow some money?
我能借点钱吗？
Sure, let me give you my pen.
当然，我把笔给你。
Let me give you my money.
我把钱给你。
Okay.
好的。
But wait, giving is different, because giving means I don't have to get it back.
但等等，“给”是不同的，因为“给”意味着我不需要拿回来。
Right.
对。
So if you want to give it to someone temporarily, then you lend them your pen, or you lend them
所以如果你暂时给别人东西，那就是你把笔借给他们，或者你把钱借给他们。
some money.
一些钱。
Great.
太好了。
So to borrow is to take something from someone, knowing that you will have to give it back
所以“借入”就是从某人那里拿东西，知道以后要还回去。
later.
对。
Right.
而“借出”就是把东西给别人，对吧？
And to lend is to give it to someone, right?
所以你能借我你的笔吗？
So can you lend me your pen?
意思是你能把它给我吗？
That means can you give it to me, please?
对。
Right.
这是语言学习者常犯的错误，尤其是英语学习者，
And this is a common mistake with language learners, especially English learners, that
他们常把“借入”和“借出”用混。
they make the mistake of using borrow instead of lend.
所以你能借我点钱吗？
So can you borrow me some money?
对。
Right.
所以你能借我点钱吗？
So can you lend me some money?
当然，但我希望你以后还我。
Sure, but I expect you to pay me back later.
好的，非常好。
Okay, very good.
如果我以后还你，我会加上利息。
And if I pay you back later, I'll include an interest rate.
好的。
Will you really?
你真的会吗？
No, not really.
不，其实不会。
Mostly it's banks that ask for an interest rate.
大多数情况下是银行要求利率。
So in this case, an interest rate means the amount of money that a bank will charge you
所以在这个语境下，利率指的是银行会向你收取的额外费用，
in addition to the money that you owe them.
除了你欠他们的钱之外。
Exactly.
没错。
So it's called an interest rate and it's a rate because it's a percentage.
所以它叫利率，之所以叫“率”是因为它是一个百分比。
So it's like 5%.
比如5%。
Exactly.
没错。
5, 10%.
5%、10%。
That is an interest rate.
这就是利率。
And now moving on, if you have a loan and you have to pay each month, be careful to
现在继续，如果你有一笔贷款并且需要每月还款，要小心
not default on your payments.
不要拖欠还款。
Okay, default.
好的，拖欠。
In the banking world, this means to not be able to pay your loan.
在银行业，这指的是无法偿还贷款。
So that means that if I owe $1,000 to you, Bank of Marco, and I don't have the money,
也就是说，如果我欠你——马可银行——1000美元，但我没钱，
I can't pay for it, then I default.
我付不起，那我就拖欠了。
So to be late or to not make the payment.
所以就是逾期或未付款。
It's a verb, to default.
它是一个动词，拖欠。
Very good.
非常好。
And Will, the person asking for the loan has a small problem.
而威尔，那个申请贷款的人，有个小问题。
His credit score is not very good.
他的信用评分不太好。
Okay, I think he calls it terrible.
好吧，我觉得他称之为糟糕。
And one of the ways that you get a terrible credit score is by defaulting on a loan.
导致信用评分糟糕的一个原因就是拖欠贷款。
But it also means that maybe you borrow money or you have credit cards and you can't pay
但也可能意味着你借钱或持有信用卡，却无法
off your bills.
还清账单。
And so a credit score is very important in America and it's like a report card for your
所以信用评分在美国非常重要，它就像你财务状况的
finances.
成绩单。
Right.
对。
So for example, if your credit score is a report card and you have an A credit score,
比如，如果你的信用评分是成绩单，并且得了A，
that means that the banks won't have a problem with lending you money.
那就意味着银行借钱给你不会有问题。
Or if you want to buy a new car, it'll be okay.
或者如果你想买辆新车，也没问题。
But if you don't pay your bills on time or you default on your loans, then maybe you'll
但如果你不按时还账单或拖欠贷款，那么你可能
have a C or a D and then people will not really lend you money in the future.
会得C或D，以后人们就不太愿意借钱给你了。
They won't trust you.
他们不会信任你。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, so that's credit score.
好了，这就是信用评分。
That's all the words we have for Fluency Builder.
这就是我们“流利度构建”部分的所有词汇。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back shortly.
我们再来听一遍对话，一会儿回来。
Hello, sir.
您好，先生。
May I help you?
有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes, I would like some information for requesting a loan.
是的，我想了解一些申请贷款的信息。
Very well.
好的。
Here are the general terms of our loan policies.
这是我们贷款政策的一般条款。
We pride ourselves in having the lowest interest rate in the country for personal loans.
我们以拥有全国最低的个人贷款利率而自豪。
I see.
我明白了。
So let me get this straight.
让我确认一下。
If I borrow, let's say, $10,000, how much will I have to pay each month?
如果我借，比如说，一万美元，我每个月要还多少钱？
It depends on how long you take to pay it back.
这取决于你多久还清。
If we lend you $10,000 at an annual interest rate of 10% for 48 months, you would have
如果我们借给你一万美元，年利率10%，分48个月还，你每个月需要
to pay each month a portion of the loan, which is called the principal, and another small
还一部分贷款，这叫做本金，再加上一小部分
portion of the annual interest rate.
年利率。
This of course is considering that you don't default on a payment.
当然，这是假设你没有违约还款。
It sounds good, but there's just one problem.
听起来不错，但有一个问题。
I have a terrible credit score.
我的信用评分很差。
That is a very serious problem, you see.
你看，这是个非常严重的问题。
The bank must assess your personal information, past loans, assets, and any other relevant
银行必须评估你的个人信息、过往贷款、资产以及任何其他相关
information such as your credit score in order to approve your loan.
信息，比如你的信用评分，才能批准你的贷款。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I don't really need the money.
我其实并不需要这笔钱。
Thanks anyways.
不过还是谢谢了。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now, why don't we take a look at three key phrases on Fluency Builder.
那么现在，我们来看看“流利度构建”中的三个关键短语。
Let me get this straight.
让我确认一下。
We're going to do Fluency Builder?
我们要做“流利度构建”吗？
That's right.
没错。
Wait, I don't.
等等，我不……
Wait.
等等。
So, okay.
那么，好吧。
So this is our first phrase.
这是我们的第一个短语。
Let me get this straight, and this is a fixed phrase that means we always say it the same
“让我确认一下”，这是一个固定短语，意思是我们总是以同样的方式说它。
way.
方式。
Wait, let me get this straight.
等等，让我确认一下。
We always say it the same way?
我们总是以同样的方式说它？
Right, so you're asking for a confirmation or you're repeating what that person said
对，所以你在请求确认，或者你在重复那个人说的话，
just to be sure that it's correct.
只是为了确保它是正确的。
Exactly.
完全正确。
So, maybe you don't understand something or maybe you think you might have misunderstood.
所以，也许你不明白某事，或者你认为你可能误解了。
You say, hey, so let me get this straight, and you repeat what the person just said.
你会说，嘿，让我确认一下，然后重复那个人刚才说的话。
It's a way for you to, like you say, get confirmation on what you've heard.
这是一种方式，就像你说的，对你听到的内容进行确认。
Very good.
非常好。
Let me get this straight.
让我确认一下。
And now, moving on, we have the phrase, pay it back.
现在，继续，我们有短语“还清”。
You have to pay it back.
你必须还清它。
Okay, and so in this case, we have the verb to pay, but we also have the word back.
好的，在这种情况下，我们有动词“支付”，但我们还有单词“回”。
So pay it back means to repay.
所以“还清”意思是偿还。
So if we take out a loan, we obviously have to pay it back to the bank.
所以如果我们贷款，显然我们必须把钱还给银行。
Right, so you have to pay the loan back.
对，所以你必须还清贷款。
Okay, so just remember that these words often go together, to pay it back.
好的，所以请记住这些词经常一起出现，“还清”。
I'll pay you back, I promise.
我会还你的，我保证。
Right, can you lend me a dollar?
对，你能借我一美元吗？
I'll pay you back tomorrow.
我明天还你。
Nah, don't worry about it.
不用，别担心。
Alright, and the bank started off saying, we pride ourselves in having the lowest interest
好的，银行一开始说，我们以拥有全国最低的利率
rate in the country.
而自豪。
Yeah, right.
是啊，没错。
Alright, so we pride ourselves.
好的，所以我们以……为自豪。
What does it mean if I pride myself in something?
如果我以某事为自豪，那是什么意思？
The word pride means to be really happy about something that has to do with yourself.
“自豪”这个词意味着对与自己有关的某事感到非常高兴。
So something that you're proud of is something that you want to tell a lot of other people
所以让你感到骄傲的事情是你想告诉很多其他人
about.
的事情。
For example, a father may say, my son just got straight A's and he's an excellent soccer
例如，一位父亲可能会说，我儿子刚得了全优，而且他还是个出色的足球
player and so he's proud of his son.
运动员，所以他为儿子感到骄傲。
But to pride oneself means to be really happy with the way that you do something.
但“以……为自豪”意味着对自己做事的方式感到非常满意。
Right, so for example, if I've never smoked, right?
对，例如，如果我从不抽烟，对吧？
So I can say, I pride myself in being a non-smoker.
所以我可以这样说，我以自己不抽烟为自豪。
Or I could say, I pride myself in always saving lots of money for my paycheck.
或者我可以说，我以自己总是从工资中省下很多钱为自豪。
Very good.
非常好。
So it means I try to do this because I know it's a good thing.
所以这意味着我努力这样做，因为我知道这是件好事。
But you feel very good about this and you feel that people should be proud of you as
但你对此感觉非常好，并且你觉得人们也应该为你感到骄傲。
well.
骄傲。
So we could ask our students here, what do you pride yourselves in as a challenge?
所以我们可以问问我们的学生，你们以什么为自豪，作为一个挑战？
As a challenge for the website.
作为网站的一个挑战。
Alright, so why don't we listen to the dialogue for the last time and we'll be back.
好的，那么让我们最后一次听对话，然后我们再回来。
Hello sir, may I help you?
您好先生，有什么可以帮您的吗？
Yes.
是的。
Would you like some information for requesting a loan?
您想了解一些申请贷款的信息吗？
Very well.
好的。
Here are the general terms of our loan policies.
这是我们贷款政策的一般条款。
We pride ourselves in having the lowest interest rate in the country for personal loans.
我们以拥有全国最低的个人贷款利率而自豪。
I see.
我明白了。
So let me get this straight.
所以让我确认一下。
If I borrow, let's say, $10,000, how much will I have to pay each month?
如果我借，比如说，一万美元，我每个月要还多少钱？
It depends on how long you take to pay it back.
这取决于你多久还清。
If we lend you $10,000 at an annual interest rate of 10% for 48 months, you would have
如果我们借给你一万美元，年利率10%，分48个月还，你每个月需要
to pay each month a portion of the loan, which is called the principal, and another small
还一部分贷款，这叫做本金，再加上一小部分
portion of the annual interest rate.
年利率。
This of course is considering that you don't default on a payment.
当然，这是假设你没有违约还款。
It sounds good, but there's just one problem.
听起来不错，但有一个问题。
I have a terrible credit score.
我的信用评分很差。
That is a very serious problem, you see.
你看，这是个非常严重的问题。
The bank must assess your personal information, past loans, assets, and any other relevant
银行必须评估你的个人信息、过往贷款、资产以及任何其他相关
information, such as your credit score, in order to approve your loan.
信息，比如你的信用评分，才能批准你的贷款。
You know what?
你知道吗？
I don't really need the money.
我其实并不需要这笔钱。
Thanks anyways.
不过还是谢谢了。
Alright, very good.
好的，非常好。
So as you say, saving is important.
所以就像你说的，储蓄很重要。
And well, sometimes, do you think you need a loan?
嗯，有时候，你觉得你需要贷款吗？
I think sometimes people need loans because they want to go into business, for example.
我认为有时候人们需要贷款，因为他们想创业，比如说。
So people who want to go into small businesses or open their own companies need startup capital.
所以想从事小生意或开自己公司的人需要启动资金。
This is a really great example of when people don't have the money lying around and will
这是一个很好的例子，说明当人们手头没有闲钱时，
go to find a bank that will give them a loan.
会去找银行给他们贷款。
So yeah, I think it's really important, especially for the economy of a country, for business
所以是的，我认为这非常重要，尤其对一个国家的经济来说，商业
loans or small business loans to be available because sometimes it's very difficult to find
贷款或小企业贷款应该可得，因为有时候很难找到
a bank that will actually lend a person money to start a business.
一家银行真的愿意借钱给人创业。
Usually they won't have a problem with lending them money to buy a new car, but to start
通常他们不会介意借钱给人买新车，但创业
up a business, it's completely the opposite.
则完全相反。
It is.
确实如此。
And one of the really popular trends in foreign investment right now is called micro-lending,
现在外国投资中一个非常流行的趋势叫做小额贷款，
so micro-loans.
也就是微型贷款。
And that means that if I want to help people in a very poor country, I can lend $100 for
这意味着如果我想帮助一个非常贫穷的国家的人，我可以借出100美元
someone to buy a sewing machine or for someone to buy a small computer, $500 for a small
让人买台缝纫机，或者让人买台小电脑，500美元买台小
computer, and that is a micro-loan.
电脑，这就是微型贷款。
It's a very, very small loan for one thing, and that can help them towards their goal
这是一笔非常非常小的贷款，用于一件事，可以帮助他们朝着成为
of being a business person.
商人的目标前进。
Right.
对。
And you're not really getting money out of it, though.
但你其实不会从中赚钱。
You're not charging like 100% interest rate.
你不会收取像100%那样的高利率。
You're not.
你不是。
You're charging like 1 or 2% interest, very low interest, and you're giving people a chance
你只收1%或2%的利息，非常低的利息，而且你给了人们一个机会
to pay the money back because it's such a small amount.
去还钱，因为金额很小。
Wow, that's really good.
哇，那真不错。
A really positive thing.
一件非常积极的事情。
Very good.
非常好。
So if you have any questions, any comments, or any suggestions, please come to our website
所以如果你有任何问题、任何评论或任何建议，请访问我们的网站
at EnglishPod.com, and we'll see you guys there.
EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里见你们。
Bye, everyone.
大家再见。
See you next time.
下次见。